Jian Gao

Email: jian gao@whu.edu.cn
[Website] [Google Scholar]

I will graduate from Wuhan University in June 2023 with a Master's degree under the supervision of Prof. Shunping Ji. My current research interests are focused on *deep learning based multi-view stereo*, 3D reconstruction from optical satellite images and drone images and other 3D related topics.

Education

M.S. Pattern Recognition and Intelligent Systems

Sept. 2020 – June 2023

Wuhan University

Wuhan, Hubei, China

School of Remote Sensing and Information Engineering

Thesis: Research on Learning Based Dense Match Algorithm for Multi-View Optical Satellite Images Supervised by Prof. Shunping Ji

B.S. Science and Technology of Remote Sensing Wuhan University

Sept.2016 – June 2020

Wuhan, Hubei, China

School of Remote Sensing and Information Engineering

GPA: 3.86 / 4.0 Rank: 6 / 201

Publications

[1] **J. Gao**, J. Liu and S. Ji, "Rational Polynomial Camera Model Warping for Deep Learning Based Satellite Multi-View Stereo Matching," 2021 IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), Montreal, QC, Canada, 2021, pp. 6128-6137, doi: 10.1109/ICCV48922.2021.00609.

[2] **J. Gao**, J. Liu, and S. Ji, "A general deep learning based framework for 3D reconstruction from multi-view stereo satellite images," ISPRS Journal of Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, vol. 195, pp. 446–461, Jan. 2023, doi: 10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2022.12.012. (IF: 11.774)

Work Experience

Teaching Assistant

Feb. 2020 – July. 2020 & Feb. 2021 – July. 2021

Course: Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition

Lecture: Practical guidance for 3D reconstruction based on multi-view stereo images

Research Skills

Experienced in photogrammetry and multi-view 3D reconstruction.

Experienced in C/C++, Python. Familiar with PyTorch, OpenCV and CUDA.

Hours & Awards

Wang Zhizhuo innovative talent scholarship	Dec. 20th, 2019
First Class Entrance Scholarship for New Students	Sept. 10th, 2020
Outstanding Graduates	May 4th, 2020
Excellent Student Cadre	May 4th, 2019
8 th Asian and Pacific Mathematical Contest in Modeling (First Prize)	Jan. 28th, 2019
9th MatherCup College Mathematical Modeling Challenge (Second Prize)	Jun. 5th, 2019